<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Michał Koczorowski</title>
		<link>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Michał Koczorowski</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 19:13:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Google CTF Begginers Quest Writeup</title>
			<link>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/google-ctf-begginers-quest-writeup/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 19:13:48 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/google-ctf-begginers-quest-writeup/</guid>
			<description>How I spent definitely too much time on an begginer capture the flag. Last weekend,while scrolling twitter I saw the post about Google CTF. Of course I am not qualified to solve it, I clearly do not have much needed experience with such competitions and programming as a whole. After checking it out I stumbled upon an &amp;ldquo;Google CTF begginers quest&amp;rdquo; and tasks here looked like they were not that hard.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="how-i-spent-definitely-too-much-time-on-an-begginer-capture-the-flag">How I spent definitely too much time on an begginer capture the flag.</h2>
<p>Last weekend,while scrolling twitter I saw the post about Google CTF. Of course I am not qualified to solve it, I clearly do not have much needed experience with such competitions and programming as a whole. After checking it out I stumbled upon an <a href="https://capturetheflag.withgoogle.com/beginners-quest" title="CTF">&ldquo;Google CTF begginers quest&rdquo;</a> and tasks here looked like they were not that hard.</p>
<h2 id="just-secret-agent-things">Just secret agent things</h2>
<p>So after my introduction to my new role as a spy I quickly grabbed a friend and we started to get going with the first task.</p>
<h2 id="novosibirsk---cttv-hacking">Novosibirsk - CTTV hacking</h2>
<p>First we were tasked with, breaking into a monitoring system of some super secret facility, secured by famous cybersecurity company &ldquo;YesWeAreSecure™&rdquo;. First thing I done was viewing the source code and look what I found, a javacript that checks the password. <img src="static/source-cctv.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Then I concluded that the numbers in the starting with 52xx were ASCII characters and all left to do was to substract 0xCafe from that. The password I got was</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>GoodPassword
</code></pre><p>which took me to the page with the flag:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>CTF{IJustHopeThisIsNotOnShodan}
</code></pre>]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Automating Blog Updates</title>
			<link>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/automating-blog-updates/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 14:30:09 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/automating-blog-updates/</guid>
			<description>How I update my blog with a stupid simple ten line bash script. This post can sound like stating the obvious, but if something can be done by script, it is better decision to automate it. When I finished setting up the whole website, I had to solve one annoying problem. Do I really have to input like 9 separate commands and switch between directories to update just one blog post?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="how-i-update-my-blog-with-a-stupid-simple-ten-line-bash-script">How I update my blog with a stupid simple ten line bash script.</h2>
<p>This post can sound like stating the obvious, but if something can be done by script, it is better decision to automate it. When I finished setting up the whole website, I had to solve one annoying problem. Do I really have to input like 9 separate commands and switch between directories to update just one blog post?</p>
<p>Prior to it I didn&rsquo;t have any experience scripting in bash, of course I used install scripts for some software and knew I had to give scripts some permissions, but it was a whole new thing for me.
I expected that script would be somewhat different than just using terminal, but it turns out it&rsquo;s just the same. Of course I can make variables, loops and all of this useful stuff, but all i needed was to have some commands executed.</p>
<h2 id="so-how-it-looks">So how it looks?</h2>
<p>Honestly? I know this could be done better but I just copied my terminal history from the last time i was updating and pasted it into <em>.sh</em> file.</p>
<p>And that&rsquo;s it. All  done in less than a minute.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>  1 #!/bin/bash                                                                          
  2 
  3 cd blog
  4 git add .
  5 git commit -m &quot;script updating&quot;
  6 git push
  7 hugo -d ../m-koczorowski.github.io
  8 cd ../m-koczorowski.github.io
  9 git add .
 10 git commit -m &quot;scripts updating&quot;
 11 git push

</code></pre>]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>My first blog post</title>
			<link>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/first-post/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://m-koczorowski.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid>
			<description>Introduction This is my first post on this blog. Here I will share thigns I find interestig and my thoughts.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>This is my first post on this blog. Here I will share thigns I find interestig and my thoughts.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
